Bjørn Tore Svinningen

Heliveien 945, 1820 Spydeberg, Norway

Phone: +47 90516604

Mail: postmannen@gmail.com | twitter: twitter.com/erter1 | github: github.com/postmannen |

linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bj%C3%B8rn-tore-svinningen-1394816/

Summary

A tech-savvy individual with a passion for learning new things and exploring diverse fields, including programming, IT, psychology, economy, art, music, electronics, hydraulics, farming, and more. In 2017, I decided to focus on Go development as the primary area of expertise. My broad experience allows me to

approach problems from various angles, ensuring successful product development and effective resolution of complex issues within project teams.

I first started programming in Pascal about 3 decades ago, but things happened and my main work became networks and servers, where programming was something I continued to do, but occasionally. In 2017 I decided to switch that around, and do development as the main thing.

Professional Experience

Been working with Data centers, Network, Security, Servers, and Monitoring since 1997, and made the switch to fulltime Development in 2017.

Building Edge Cloud solutions from the ground and up.

The most recent jobs can be found below.

Jul 2023 - Present, Selfstudy eBPF.

- Study eBPF, tracing, handling network traffic on Linux servers.
- · Al in the form of llama.
- · Security.

Jan 2020 - Jun 2023 Raa Labs, Contract

- Build an Edge Cloud infrastructure/platform from the ground up for ships sailing around the globe.
- Create an event driven infrastructure controller, Steward for RaaLabs
- K3s.
- Created various tools and automation services, where most of the services with an MIT license can be found at Raalabs's Github

2017 - 2019, Study programming.

· Go, Software Architecture, and more.

2004 - Present, Self Employee, Freelance

- Go / Golang Development.
- · Automation and orchestration.
- Network and server monitoring.
- Network lan / wan & security.
- · Linux systems.
- IOT

2013 - 2017, Datametrix AS, Senior Network Consultant

- Network/Security architecture done with Cisco, Checkpoint and F5 on Datametrix's Cloud provider network.
- Network and services monitoring based on Centreon/Nagios.
- Automation and orchestration of cloud services
- Scripting/Programming in Perl and JavaScript.
- Design and implementation of Monitoring platform counting 40k+ monitored services.

2012 - 2013, IPsoft, Senior Network Consultant

- Senior Network Consultant.
- Technical Project Lead.
- Monitoring and Automation.

2008 - 2012, Steria AS, Senior Network Consultant

Network Design, implementation and management.

- Implementation projects of large and smaller customers: Planning, migration, customer relationship.
- Maintenance of Steria's datacenter's based on Cisco hardware.
- Network monitoring based on Centreon/Nagios.

2004 - 2008, Nortura, Senior Network Consultant

- Responsible for Lan/Wan, Security.
- Maintainance and implementation of Linux and Windows servers.
- System monitoring based on Centreon/Nagios and other monitoring tools available on the Linux platform.

2004 - 2004, Systeam, System Consultant

Maintainance of customer network, servers and computers.

1997 - 2003, Telenor Mobil, System Consultant

- · Network and server maintenance.
- · Customer support.

Technical Experience

I like to know how technology and the value chain work as a whole. Other areas where i have good experience are:

- · Operating systems with services: Linux and Windows.
- Monitoring systems.
- Logging systems.

Industries and verticals

- IT Data Center, Service Provider and Cloud.
- · Telecom.
- Farming and food production.
- · Shipping.

My Side Project

 Use Drones, IOT, and Code to get better control and results in agriculture. Writing a driver/controller for Parrot drones from scratch. parrot driver in Go

Open Source

 All my code and learning material are put available on Github. Hopefully for others to use, learn from, or for detecting issues in the code I have yet to know of.

Some more examples below

- Async management of servers/endpoints using Nats where everything is done with passing messages and concurrent. Steward
- Traffic sniffer who lets you know what your computer communicated with, and how much data transfered. trafficmonitor
- Driver for Parrot drones. parrot

Things I plan to look more into in the future

- Use of Go with embedded devices and micro controllers.
- Read and analyze Network Data with Go.

Education

1991-1995, Electronics, Certificate Of Apprenticeship

 1991-1995 Electronics, Computer Technical/Hardware, Micro controllers, Pascal, ASM, Audio/Video.

Languages

- Norwegian (native speaker)
- English